Guide to the Skagit County Oral History Project records 1962-1979
Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
Skagit County Oral History Project records
1962-1979
Center for Pacific Northwest Studies Goltz-Murray Building 808 25th St Bellingham, WA 98225-9123 Phone: 360 650 7534 Email: cpnws@wwu.edu
XOE_CPNWS0235SkagitOHP
Skagit County Historical Society
5 microfilm reels
This is a collection of microfilmed copies of oral history interview transcripts. The interviews were conducted by the Skagit County Historical Society between 1962 and 1979. Topics covered include social life, historical change, politics, agriculture, fishing, and timber.
This is a collection of microfilmed copies of oral history interview transcripts. The interviews were conducted by the Skagit County Historical Society between 1962 and 1979. Topics covered include social life, historical change, politics, agriculture, fishing, and timber.
This collection is entirely in microfilm format. Original recordings and transcripts were maintained by the Skagit County Historical Society.
The collection is open to the public (appointments highly recommended for access to microform reader).
The Skagit County Historical Society and Museum in LaConner, Washington, houses the original interview audio recordings and transcripts.
Donated by the Skagit County Historical Society
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Skagit County (Wash.)--History--Sources; Skagit County (Wash.)--Social life and customs--History--Sources
Agriculture--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources; Canned fish industry--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources; Depressions--1929--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources; Education--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources; Fisheries--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources; Frontier and pioneer life--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources; Indians of North America--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources; Logging--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources; Mines and mineral resources--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources; Distilling, Illicit--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources; Mountaineering--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources; Norwegian Americans--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources; Pioneers--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources; Prohibition--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources; Prospecting--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources; Prostitution--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources; Smuggling--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources; Tribes--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources; World War, 1939-1945--Washington (State)--Skagit County--History--Sources
Oral Histories
- Nora Hastie (Year of Birth: 1877) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-1, a & b (Reel 1)
  Format: Transcript (number of pages not listed), Cassette (time not listed), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Homesteading, Schools, Anacortes, Edison.
  Notes: Two tapes and one transcript.
- Iver Youngquist (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-2 (Reel 1)
- Alfred Polson [Mrs. Al Polson] (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-3 (Reel 1)
  Subjects: Fir Island, Brown's Slough, Polson Farm
- Nell Quackenbush (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-4 (Reel 1)
  Subjects: Telephone Co. - owner/operator/repairman/lineman
- Museum Cornerstone interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-5 (Reel 1)
- Mary O'Loughlin, Lou Valentine, Lillian O'Loughlin Wall (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-6 (Reel 1)
- Fred March (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-7 (Reel 1)
- William Good [Mrs. William Good] (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-8 (Reel 1)
  Format: Transcript (number of pages not listed), Reel-to-reel (time not listed)
  Subjects: Homesteading, Fir Island, came west in 1895
- Leo Whitney (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-9 (Reel 1)
- Anna Callahan Woodruff (Year of Birth: 1870) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-10 (Reel 1)
  Subjects: Fredonia, Whitney, March's Point, Indians
- Hamilton Old-Timers (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-11 (Reel 1)
- Joshua Green (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-12 (Reel 1)
- Joshua Green (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-13 (Reel 1)
- Morris Johnson (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-14 (Reel 1)
- H. G. Pulsipher (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-15 (Reel 1)
  Format: Transcript, Cassette (time not listed), Reel-to-reel
- Mrs. H. G. Pulsipher (Year of Birth: 1892) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-16 (Reel 1)
  Subjects: Birdsview, Concrete, Equality Colony
- Raymond Conn (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-17 (Reel 1)
- William Gill (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-18 (Reel 1)
- Ethel Van Fleet Harris (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-19 (Reel 1)
  Subjects: Indians, Sedro-Woolley, to Skagit in 1880
- Mrs. Motz Hamilton (Year of Birth: 1873) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-20 (Reel 1)
  Subjects: Hamilton, Schools, Disease, Churches, Rivers
- Mrs. E. G. Stewart [Mrs. E. S. Stewart] (Year of Birth: 1863) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-21 (Reel 1)
  Subjects: Mt. Vernon, Riverside, Railroad, Maritime
- Irene Schumaker (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-22 (Reel 1)
  Subjects: Edison area, Edison Catholic Church
- Ebba Hamburg [Mrs. Ebba Olson] (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-23 (Reel 1)
  Subjects: Mt. Vernon, First Baptist Church, B. N. L. Davis
- Gar Green (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-24 (Reel 1)
- Mrs. George Bernhoft (Year of Birth: 1894) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-25 (Reel 1)
  Subjects: Avon, Homesteading, 1890s Depression
- Mrs. Charles Olson (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-26 (Reel 1)
  Subjects: Pleasant Ridge, Fir Island, LaConner
- Ira Savage (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-27 (Reel 1)
  Notes: One tape and transcript including interview and instructions on running tape machine, the latter only on tape
- Francis Tillinghast (Year of Birth: 1886) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-28 (Reel 1)
  Subjects: Padilla, Florence, LaConner, Maritime
- J. O. Rudene (Hazel Hartman reading his records) (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-29 (Reel 1)
- Lyman Gathering (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-30 (Reel 1)
- Eva McGlinn Jenne (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-31 (Reel 1)
  Subjects: Midwifery, Hotels, LaConner, Schools, Indians
- Martha Parker (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-32, a, b (Reel 1)
  Subjects: Homesteading, Coupeville, Mt. Vernon
  Notes: Two tapes and one transcript
- Glenn Stover (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-33 (Reel 1)
- Andy Loft (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-34, a, b (Reel 1)
  Subjects: Two tapes and one transcript
- Martin Sampson (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-34
  Format: Cassette (time not listed), Reel-to-reel
  Notes: Included on last half of tape "b"; not transcribed
- George Hopley (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-35 (Reel 1)
- C. S. Phillips (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-36 (Reel 1)
- James Ovenell (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-37 (Reel 1)
- Jack Davis (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-38 (Reel 1)
- Harriet Wade Rowley (Year of Birth: 1880) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-39 (Reel 1)
  Subjects: Pioneer nurse of the Skagit Valley
- Francis Davis Hayton (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: unknown, Undated; RIII-40 (Reel 1)
  Subjects: Whidbey Island, Grandfather came west in 1845
- Vera Cornelius Moa (Year of Birth: 1895) interviewed by: unknown, April 20, 1962; RIII-41 (Reel 1)
  Format: Transcript (7 pages), Cassette (25 min.), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Family history
  Restrictions: none
- Mark Gilkey (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Barbara Heacock, July 15, 1977; July 22, 1977; November 4, 1977; January 11, 1978; March 30, 1978; RIII-42, T 1, 3-5 (Reel 1)
  Format: Transcript (162 pages), Cassette (7 hours 30 min), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Early Edison, Gilkey Towing, Hunting, Wobblies, Sporting girls of Edison, Card game dealer in Skagit County, Founding of Bow Hill, Gumboat Jimmy, One-eyed Mary, Lucille - Anacortes madam, Equality, Colony, Mining, Ox logging, Rum running
  Notes: Three tapes and four transcripts, including four interviews
- Clara and William Propst (Year of Birth: 1891) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Barbara Heacock, July 21, 1977; RIII-43 (Reel 1)
  Format: Transcript (59 pages), Cassette (1 hour 40 min), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Early history of Anacortes, Canning, Canneries, Traps, Fishing, Fish pirates, Shingle Mills
- Effie Leyde (Year of Birth: 1893) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Barbara Heacock, July 21, 1977; RIII-44 (Reel 1)
  Format: Transcript (4 pages), Cassette (30 min), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Granddaughter of pioneer John Pike (of Seattle), Columbia School (attended), Early Guemes, Eden Ranch life, Recipes for smoking salmon
- Edna Moe (Year of Birth: 1905) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, July 29, 1977; RIII-45 (Reel 1)
  Format: Transcript (8 pages), Cassette (1 hour), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Early Anacortes, School teacher, Chasing fires, Father ran cannery where she worked as a child
- Alice Newland (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, July 29, 1977; RIII-46 (Reel 1)
  Format: Transcript (10 pages), Cassette (1 hour), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Early Anacortes, School teacher in Anacortes, University of Washington physics degree, Father ran lumber mill and was a well known safety engineer
- Helen Loop (Year of Birth: 1895) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Barbara Heacock, August 8, 1977; RIII-47 (Reel 1)
  Format: Transcript (26 pages), Cassette (1 hour), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Anacortes, Childhood at Point Roberts, Guemes, Samish Island, Edison, Chinese, Holidays
- Minnie Studebaker (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Barbara Heacock, August 8, 1977; RIII-48 (Reel 1)
  Format: Transcript (26 pages), Cassette (1 hour 15 min), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: moved to Skagit County in 1923, Immigration from Missouri, Indian life, Colville Indian Reservation, Life on a stump ranch
- Clara and Gar Green (Year of Birth: 1905 [Clara]) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Barbara Heacock, August 5, 1977; September 2, 1977; January 13, 1978; RIII-49, T 1-3 (Reel 1)
  Format: Transcript (89 pages), Cassette (4 hours 15 min), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Early Skagit Valley, Pole logging, Rodeos, Cowboys, Pioneer home/family life, Homesteading in Alberta, Montana
  Notes: Two tapes and three transcripts, dates don't quite match
- George and Tillie Coble (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Barbara Heacock, August 10, 1977; RIII-50 (Reel 1)
  Format: Transcript (32 pages), Cassette (1 hour), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Equality Colony, Gilkey's, Edward P. Morrow's house, Bellingham [Noram?], Cooking, Came from Eastern Tennessee
- Glee Davis (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Barbara Heacock, 10, 31 aug 1977; RIII-51, T 1, 2 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (78 pages), Cassette (6 hours), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Coming upriver, Homesteading, Goodell's Landing, Ruby Creek washout, Miner's Hotel, D. Kinsey, Early mining, Family history
  Notes: Three tapes and two transcripts, interviewee restrictions lifted
  tape only
- Oleah Heise (Year of Birth: 1890) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Barbara Heacock and Bill Weaver, August 10, 1977; RIII-52 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (39 pages), Cassette (1 hour 45 min), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Diking, Conn School, Skagit Flats, Husband at Neah Bay and in service of Kaiser Wilhelm
- Freda Lipke (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Barbara Heacock, August 15, 1977; August 23, 1977; RIII-53 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (3 pages), Cassette (3 hours), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Early Anacortes, Swedish families, Chinese in the canneries
- Bess Conn Fields Rogers (Year of Birth: 1900) interviewed by: Barbara Heacock, August 16, 1977; RIII-54 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (42 pages), Cassette (1 hour 15 min), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Early Edison, Parents, Indians, Graveling roads, Farm life, Edison Bank Robbery
- Martha Gail Bishop (Year of Birth: 1892) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, August 17, 1977; RIII-55 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (18 pages), Cassette (1 hour), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Early telephone operator, grocery store owner, Coming west from Iowa, Seattle fire of 1889, Early remembrances of Seattle and Everett
- Mae Sparks (Year of Birth: 1890) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, August 17, 1977; RIII-56 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (17 pages), Cassette(30 min on side 2 of RIII-55), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: West from Arkansas in 1917, D. Kinsey portrait, Clearing for farm in Lyman, Husband was a bucker
- Maud Dever Hopley (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, August 17, 1977; RIII-57 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (21 pages), Cassette (1 hour), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Running egg farm while husband was away, Tug boating, Oyster business, Atlanta settlement, Samish Island
- Pearl Park (Year of Birth: 1896) interviewed by: Barbara Heacock, August 23, 1977; RIII-58 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (14 pages), Reel-to-reel (1 hour)
  Subjects: Indians, Cannery work, entertainment, Gaches mansion, Childhood on Fir Island, LaConner, Basket Socials
- George Loop (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, August 23, 1977; RIII-59 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (21 pages), Reel-to-reel (1 hour)
  Subjects: Early Samish, Threshing, Sack sewer, Working on an orchard farm
- Fred Martin (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, August 25, 1977; RIII-60, a, b (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (57 pages), Cassette (1 hour 45 min), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Homesteading, Schooling, Legislative career
  Notes: One tape and two transcripts, interviewee restrictions lifted
- Rona Pressentin (Year of Birth: 1888) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, August 25, 1977; January 13, 1978; RIII-61, T1a, b-2 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (64 pages), Cassette (2 hours 30 min), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Early Rockport, Upper Skagit River Area
  Notes: One tape and three transcripts, dates don't match
- Alle Rozema (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Barbara Heacock, August 30, 1977; RIII-62
  Format: Cassette (2 hours), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Wagon maker apprentice, Shipyard work in Holland, Immigration after WWII to Canada - then to US
  Notes: not transcribed
- Mr. and Mrs. Arne Johnson (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Barbara Heacock, August 31, 1977; RIII-63 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (41 pages), Reel-to-reel (1 hour 30 min)
  Subjects: Farming in Edison, Norwegian community, Cultural development of Norwegian people in the US
  Notes: Interviewee restrictions - see authorization
  Restrictions: tape only
- Bert Pressentin (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Barbara Heacock, September 2, 1977; RIII-64 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (19 pages), Reel-to-reel (1 hour)
  Subjects: Pressentin family hotel, Early Rockport
- Bertha Schumaker (Year of Birth: 1890) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, September 7, 1977; RIII-65 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (17 pages), Cassette (1 hour), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Edison's first telephone operator, Early Edison area
- Charles Dinsmore (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Barbara Heacock, September 7, 1977; March 3, 1978; RIII-66, T 1-2 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (66 pages), Cassette (2 hours 40 min), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Marine, Policeman in Pike Street Market during Prohibition and the Depression, Bartender, Boston
  Notes: Two tapes and two transcripts
- Oliver Larsen (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, September 8, 1977; RIII-67 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (17 pages), Reel-to-reel (1 hour)
  Subjects: Mills, Injuries and accidents, Sawyer, First truck driver to bring in 40-lb crates of tree-ripened fruit to the Skagit Valley
- Jake Worline (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, September 13, 1977; RIII-68 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (40 pages), Cassette (2 hours), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Early threshing around the Samish Flats, Bow, Use of donkeys in the woods, Logging accidents, Immigration trains
- Jim McLean (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, September 13, 1977; RIII-69 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (39 pages), Cassette (2 hours), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Cattle ranching, Trapping, WWI, Early Oregon wheat farming
- Joe Mears (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, September 14, 1977; RIII-70 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (13 pages), Reel-to-reel (1 hour)
  Subjects: Early lime kilns, Roche Harbor, Mills and fish plants of Anacortes, Ice creamery and snack bar
- Edna Breazeale (Year of Birth: 1895) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Barbara Heacock, September 14, 1977; RIII-71 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (31 pages), Cassette (2 hours), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Early Bayview and its settlers, Padilla, Taught in a one-room schoolhouse at Padilla, Teaching, Schooling, University of Washington, Indians at Bayview
- Verna Wells (Year of Birth: 1896) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, September 15, 1977; RIII-72 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (10 pages), Cassette (1 hour 15 min), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Music, Education, Theater in Anacortes, Silent movies, Indian music transcription
- Mary P. Larsen (Year of Birth: 1901) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, September 16, 1977; RIII-73 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (56 pages), Cassette ( 2 hours 30 min), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Homesteading on the Upper Skagit, Early Schools, School teacher for 50 years, Horses, Farm life
- Franklin Thomas (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Barbara Heacock, September 16, 1977; December 15, 1977; RIII-74, T1-2 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (41 pages), Cassette (3 hours), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Sailboat Katy Thomas, Built by father and uncles, used to smuggle in Chinese and Opium
- Harvey Hopley (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, September 19, 1977; RIII-75 (Reel 2)
  Subjects: Early Samish Island, Homesteading, Schools, Tugboating, Oystering, Pilings for dikes, Booming to Edison from Gilkeys, Body hunt in the wreck of the Bahada
- Alan Tingley (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Barbara Heacock, September 20, 1977; RIII-76 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (58 pages), Reel-to-reel (2 hours)
  Subjects: Tugboating on the Skagit River, Indians, The Skagit River itself
- Frank Maddox (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, September 21, 1977; RIII-77 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (53 pages), Cassette (2 hours), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Early logging, Equipment and camera carrier for D. Kinsey, Fiddling during the Depression, Donkey engineer for thirty years.
- Sophie P. Johnson (Year of Birth: 1906) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Barbara Heacock, September 21, 1977; RIII-78 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (31 pages), Cassette (1 hour 30 min), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Early School teacher in Skagit Valley, WWII POW in Germany
- Otto Peterson (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Jim Harris, September 23, 1977; RIII-79 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (42 pages), Reel-to-reel (2 hours)
  Subjects: Early business ventures, Stage company, Automobile dealerships, Store owner, Moonshining
- Hazel and A. K. Tracey (Year of Birth: 1912) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Jim Harris, September 23, 1977; RIII-80 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (23 pages), Reel-to-reel (2 hours)
  Subjects: Early Marblemount, Schools, Working on the dam
- Bill Bessner (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Barbara Heacock, September 26, 1977, September 30, 1977; RIII-81 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (68 pages), Cassette (2 hours 45 min), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Pile driving for Fidalgo Island Packing Co., Working on a fish tender, Gilkeys, Red Reece, Rum running, Fish Pirates, Chinese, Fisherman's Packing Corporation, Guemes Island, Cod fishing, Guemes Ferry, Charlie Cann, Sporting Girls
- Eva LeMaister (Year of Birth: 1886) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, September 27, 1977; RIII-82 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (26 pages), Reel-to-reel (1 hour)
  Subjects: Homesteading, Early Guemes, Childhood on Guemes, Canneries of Anacortes, Afraid of the Chinese that worked in the boarding house kitchens.
- John Pinelli (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, September 28, 1977; RIII-83 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (43 pages), Cassette (2 hours 30 min), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Logging, Donkeys, Rigging, Early Hamilton, Homesteading at Hamilton.
- Frank and Edna Porter (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, September 28, 1977; RIII-84 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (30 pages), Cassette (2 hours), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Logging, Rockport, Early homestead on the Skagit River at Rockport, Came west when 3 days old
- Jim A. Clark, Sr. (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, September 29, 1977; February 17, 1978; RIII-85, T1a, b-2 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (101 pages), Cassette (2 hours 30 min), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Farming, Hunting, Horses, Food, Crops, Tools, The Skagit River, Recipes, Cures, Moonshining, Stills, Prohibition, Moonshine recipes.
  Notes: One tape and three transcripts
- Iola Bazinet (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Barbara Heacock, October 3, 1977; RIII-86 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (24 pages), Cassette (1 hour), Reel-to-reel
  Subjects: Midwifery, Early Marblemount, Family life, Childhood on the Upper Skagit River
- Charles Hertz (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Barbara Heacock, October 3, 1977; RIII-87 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (19 pages), Reel-to-reel (45 min)
  Subjects: Life in the Equality Colony, Getting his first job in a mill, Being on Public Assistance in 1915, Indians, Early Bow-Edison area
- Maybell Jensen (Year of Birth: 1889) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger, October 6, 1977; RIII-88 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (23 pages), Reel-to-reel (1 hour)
  Subjects: Farming, Schooling, Pleasant Ridge, Childhood in Ridgeway, Horses, Parents were from England, Father was Jeremiah Thompson, cf. 1906 History of Skagit and Snohomish Counties
- Sylvia Grimbley (Year of Birth: 1910) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Barbara Heacock, October 7, 1977; RIII-89 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (6 pages), Reel-to-reel (1 hour)
  Subjects: Growing up in Sauk Valley region
- Archie Grimbley (Year of Birth: unknown) interviewed by: Peter Hefflefinger and Barbara Heacock, October 7, 1977; RIII-90 (Reel 2)
  Format: Transcript (27 pages), Cassette (1 hour 30 min), Reel-to-reel